Go, Pietrino!
It's your turn!
Let me through!
- Pietro! Pietro!
- Does anyone have a car?
I'm sorry, madam;
you can't enter now.
The Goal of the Kingfisher
Dear Dad, something
extraordinary happened to me.
During the match
against Astra, I died.
I didn't exactly die,
but I nearly did.
They even took me
to the hospital.
Since you passed away,
something strange has got into me.
A sort of fear.
A mental block.
The first time it happened to me
was during practice.
I told the coach,
but he wouldn't believe me.
See? That's how you shoot a penalty!
Come on, go home!
Go!
Coach...
What is it?
Listen...
I think you'd better choose
someone else to shoot penalties.
Because...
I feel...
- I feel something strange.
- What do you feel?
I don't know...
I feel...
"blocked".
"Blocked"?!
Come on, Moretti!
You have good feet!
Go, go.
Go and take a shower
with the others.
I couldn't tell Mom because, as you know,
she's not happy with me playing football.
You're all wet!
Cover up.
Why are you all wet
like this?
Besides, she's always
overprotective with me.
I'm doing quite well at school,
but time passes slowly.
By the way, do you remember
Giuliano, the repeating student,
who is the goalie for Astra?
He's still flirting
with Simonetta.
But I think she's in love
with another boy.
So he picks on me.
I've never made fun of him,
yet he keeps playing
stupid tricks on me.
Maybe it bothers him that
I'm the top scorer in the team.
- Hi.
- Hi...
Relax!
The boss hasn't arrived yet.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Hey, by the way...
That German, who called
yesterday, is here again.
The usher said he's been
here since 7:00.
I take pictures of migratory birds.
Why did you seize my photo hides?
I don't understand.
They are ecological and
don't pollute the landscape.
If you don't apply for a permit,
how are we supposed to know?
Do you know how many people
would like a villa in the oasis?
It's written here: "...after submitting
a permit request to the Water Authority".
"Submitting"?
It means "presenting". You need to
present a permit request on plain paper.
- Do you want me to do that
for you? - Yes, please.
Dad, I'm embarrassed
to say this,
but to overcome the fear that has got
into me, I made a bet with Jesus.
I bet that if I managed to score
at least one goal against Astra,
I'd find you at home, sitting at the table
with Mom, and we'd talk about the match.
But you'll never sit
at the table with us again.
I think about you, Dad,
all the time,
even when I'm playing
football.
Mom feels so bad...
Sometimes she looks far away, as if
she were looking for you among a crowd.
I wish I could help her,
but I can only do so much.
Sometimes we both feel like crying,
but then we pretend nothing's happened.
Now I'll tell you
how things turned out.
- I thought this morning would never end.
- You're telling me!
- Where do we go for lunch?
To that fatso's? - No, the boss is going there;
- we'd have to have lunch with him.
- Don't worry;
he was on a long call
with the mayor.
Hey, that German is really
a handsome guy, you know?
You can have him.
He's all yours.
- Really? I'll take him, then!
- Take him!
Do you want to check?
Please...
Just wood and reeds.
- No paint. No nails.
- Ah.
- Beautiful.
- Yes, wonderful!
And this is the hole
for the telephoto lens.
You should come
and see, someday.
With your friend.
- We will.
- Yes, we will.
- There he is!
- Ah! That's Missiroli.
He's our boss.
We have to go now.
- Bye. - Auf Wiedersehen!
- Auf Wiedersehen!
Herr Missiroli...
Oh, Jesus...
What can I do for you?
Buffetti: number 4.
Cacciatori: number 5.
Pavarotti: number 6.
Trillini: number 9.
New glasses again?
It's already the 4th pair since
the start of the championship.
- What does your father say?
- That I should avoid headers.
- Coach, will Mottola play with
the number 7 jersey? - Number 11.
- That handsome German has
his eye on you. - Come on!
You know I have other things on my mind.
Besides, I don't like him.
- He has the eyes of a madman.
- He has some healthy shoulders, though!
Here I am!
The "martinet" has arrived!
May I take it?
So, how's it going?
What have you ordered?
Two tuna and tomato
sandwiches.
Tuna?
Canned food... Yuck!
It's full of preservatives.
No, I need natural food. Hey, waiter!
I've been waiting for an hour.
For me, a frittata sandwich,
spread with mayonnaise.
How disgusting!
I was detained by that German.
He's such a pain!
With his hides made of branches,
he was driving me crazy,
last year.
He got reported because he hadn't asked for
a permit. And he didn't understand a word.
- He looks harmless to me.
- Yes, he looks so defenceless.
"Defenceless"? You've never seen him
when he sets his mind on something!
This is the last match
of the first half of the season.
We're last to second
in the table, with 7 points.
38 goals conceded,
8 goals scored.
Guys, the second half of the season
is a whole another thing!
You have to listen to me! We suck
because you always do things your way!
Blackboard!
Baracchi, you'll play
in midfield, okay?
In coverage.
You'll man-mark their Number 8.
If you block him,
their manoeuvre will be
neutralized!
Astra is first in the table, but it's not
necessarily bound to win every time!
The point is that
you're embarrassing me at work,
with all your absences
and lateness...
Why don't you let me help you?
Huh?
We could go out
together sometime.
You can bring your son, too.
Pietro isn't well. He still hasn't
got over his father's death.
I know he'd need a...
I don't feel like going out, at the moment.
Thanks so much anyway.
But... can I come and
see him play next Saturday?
Yes.
I'll come for you, then!
We'll all go there by bike!
See you on Saturday!
Bye!
Every Saturday,
the same story.
I'm not hungry.
A match shouldn't cause you
so much tension.
You don't understand.
What don't I understand?
It's not mandatory for you to play.
You can do something else.
You don't play.
You can't understand.
"Astra FC vs. Audace FC."
"For Astra: Gastaldi,
Desini, Giorgetti,
"Simeoni, Fantini, Figliolo,
"Farina, Zampedri, Strozzi,
"Brasini, Sampietri."
"For Audace: Moretti,
Pavarotti, Dalbuoni,
"Gobbetti, Versari, Vianelli,
"Mottola, Caramatti, Trillini,
"Lippa, Maietti."
Today Audace is going
to score four goals!
Come on!
Careful!
Pass the ball!
Come on!
Well done, Pietro!
Go!
We're going to win, today!
Come on!
Come on, go!
Close down the space!
Go!
You imbecile!
Imbecile!
You suck!
Hey! Are we playing
in their favour?!
Go for it!
Go!
You have to win, even at the cost
of leaving your lungs on the ground!
Come on!
- Audace! Audace!
- Come on!
Hey, stay away from me!
Francesca, look who's coming!
The German is coming!
Pietro is wasted in that team!
Come on!
- Go!
Pass the ball!
Triangle!
Trian...
Ouch!
Triangle!
Go!
Ref, don't you see it's offside?
Put some glasses on!
It's not offside!
(indistinct shouting)
Go home!
- Lucky fatso!
- Who are you calling "fatso"?
Guys...
- Calm down! Calm down!
- Out! Out!
- Go!
- Come on!
Go for it!
Go!
Goal!
Yes!
Hooray!
Well done, Davide!
Now we're starting to play seriously.
Let's score another goal right away.
Come on, keep it up!
Good!
Ref!
Huh?
Penalty!
- What happened?
- Penalty...
Ref, he hit the ball!
Damn!
I bet this time we're going to draw
with the team that is first in the table!
He's going to score!
Hey, little shit...
Hello!
You're not going to score.
Wrong-foot him with a strike
into the left corner!
Get out of the box, guys.
Go, Pietrino!
It's your turn!
Oh, Christ...
Pietro!
Oh, my God!
Is he dead?
Gosh...
So, did it go in?
- "It"... what, darling?
- The penalty shot.
I get it...
He saved it.
Cheer up, guys.
Look cheerful.
"Lift up your hearts!"
It's all right.
Come on, Coach,
don't be like this. It's all right.
This is his room.
Look who's come to visit you!
- Hi. - Hi.
- Hi. Come in.
Hey, Pietro Moretti,
what's happening to you this year?
It's not bad here.
It's better than going
to school!
- Is it true that Trillini almost
scored a goal against Virtus? - No.
We lost 7-0.
- This year the odds are stacked against us.
- There's still the second half of the season.
I'll be out in two days and
I'll go back to training, won't I?
Yeah...
So you're returning
to school...
I can't play anymore, can I?
Answer me:
Now Pietro is tired.
Now he's tired.
Thanks for visiting.
- Thank you.
- Bye. - Bye.
Thank you, everyone.
Next year I'll put together
such a good team,
that we'll finish among the first
three positions, I'm telling you.
Welcome back, Pietro.
How are you?
Fine.
I'll come over at 4 p.m., then,
after swim practice.
- Hey, has your career been cut short?
- What do you want?
- "What do you want?"
- Leave him alone;
- the teacher said he needs to relax.
- He needs to relax. Poor thing!
Stay out of this;
I didn't ask for your help.
What's happening?
What are you fighting about?
Why are you treating her badly?
Apologize to her right now!
No, I'm not apologizing
to anyone.
Pietro, why are you treating
Simonetta badly?
That's enough.
Thank you.
I can confirm there's nothing
irregular. It's all right.
- Why did he faint, then?
- He had a lipothymic attack.
"Lipothymic"?
Despite its difficult name,
it's a simple nervous reflex,
that causes acceleration or
deceleration of cardiac activity,
and fainting in more
susceptible individuals.
- Could it happen again?
- It can't be ruled out.
Mom, what did he say?
Can I get back to the pitch?
Not yet.
Mom, what's wrong with me?
Nothing, darling.
You just need to calm down a bit.
We both need to calm down.
You're all right.
After what happened, Mom is getting
more and more worried.
I think the doctors told her
there's something wrong with my heart,
but she won't tell me.
I'm really afraid I won't be able
to play football anymore.
I'm sorry to disappoint you,
but I'll never get to "Serie A".
That sucks!
If life is like this, then you didn't
miss anything by dying.
Sometimes I really want to see you,
to hear your voice, to talk with you.
Bye, Dad.
Now you have to eat, huh?
Eat, I said.
Next week
I'll start training again.
Third Photographic Exhibition
"The World of Oases"
Good evening. I wanted to know
how your son's doing.
He's better, thank you.
- Where is he, now?
- At home.
- Welcome, Mr. Mayor.
- Good morning. Thank you.
- We are ready for the award ceremony.
- Excuse me.
The Jury has awarded the prize
to the photos that,
in addition to being of aesthetic
and artistic value,
document the return
to the oasis...
of the kingfisher.
Before awarding the prize to
these photos that document...
one of the most beautiful
corners of Italy,
which we are fortunate enough
to protect in our municipal territory (...)
- Where's the German?
- I don't know. He was here a minute ago.
Go and get him,
or he'll get lost.
(the mayor continues
his speech)
What are you doing here?
Are you hiding?
It's incredible!
It's beautiful.
I'm astonished.
Yes, it's beautiful,
but they're waiting for you.
Just a moment.
It's so incredibly beautiful!
We have to go.
The mayor is waiting for you.
I've waited a long time, too.
This is no time to start
a controversy. Let's go.
Everything is a problem, here.
The oasis is a problem,
bureaucracy is a problem,
building bird hides is a problem,
and even receiving
a prize is a problem, for me.
The prize goes to an extraordinary photo
of a kingfisher, taken by Mr. Hoffman,
who is joining us, at last.
Hello?
Okay, I'll eat the food
in the fridge.
Okay, don't worry.
Okay.
Bye.
Yes!
Hey!
Do you see us?
We're here!
- Come on!
- See? He even came to the party!
- Ignore him.
- Come and sit down.
Nice party, isn't it?
It's fun!
Perfect organization!
Huh?
- So?
- "So"... what?
- Shall we dance?
- Great idea, Missiroli!
Look what partner you've got!
Come on, let's go!
Aren't you dancing?
No, I'd better not dance.
Have a seat, then.
The music isn't great,
but I like dancing.
I installed my hides
in the agreed-upon locations.
Uh-uh.
- Now you have to "give" an inspection.
- We say "to make an inspection".
Sorry.
I thought maybe
you can come tomorrow,
with your son... if he's fine.
I don't think it's necessary.
If you come...
I can try to dance.
The forecast is good.
- What forecast?
- Weather forecast... Rain or shine.
Isn't this German dancing?
- No, I can't dance.
- Ah, you can't? I can.
Moretti...
Let's dance.
Maestro,
"The Polka of Love".
You know, Francesca...
I was thinking... We've known
each other for many years,
yet I don't remember
you ever telling me:
"Aldo..."
I mean...
"Aldo, you..."
In short, you've never told me
anything nice,
as if I were a ghost to you.
I'm thinking that...
maybe this means something.
Huh?
Besides...
Besides, you're a little drunk,
tonight, Mr. Missiroli.
It's because of that German, right?
I've seen how he looks at you.
- How does he look at me?
- He looks at you, but I saw you first.
No...
I was just kidding!
I'm not kidding at all. Don't you
understand you must leave me alone?
Roberto's been dead for a few months,
but it's as if he were still here.
Did you see what happened
to Pietro on the pitch?
Yes.
Exactly.
He needs a mentor.
No, he needs only me.
And I don't need someone following me
around all day. Don't you understand?
They arrived two days ago.
Beautiful.
- Is this where you took the photo of the
kingfisher? - No. You can't get there by boat.
There it is.
Do you see it? My hide is there,
among those reeds.
Come and get it.
- How old is he?
- 9 months old.
Shit!
You're a professional player!
- What team did you play for?
- For Bayern.
Do you know Munich?
Bayern Munich?
You played for Bayern Munich?!
Pietro, what are you doing?
Have you both gone nuts?
Mom, he used to play
for Bayern.
"Bayern"!
Look how sweaty you are.
Do you want to end up
in hospital again?
I'm surprised at you! Didn't you see
what happened to him while he was playing?
You don't have
any common sense!
We could go out
for a pizza, tonight.
We could invite
Simonetta, too.
That's not fair.
I wanted to stay there. I wanted...
- You don't know who Thomas is.
- And who's Thomas? A football player.
He used to play for Bayern,
Beckenbauer's team,
and you didn't even let me
play with him.
He can teach me a lot of things
that the coach...
I want to ask him to train me.
Pietro...
Maybe I haven't been
clear enough with you.
There's something I need
to tell you. Come on, sit down.
You can't play football
for a while.
You said I just couldn't play
in matches.
Yes, but you mustn't strain yourself.
You need to take care of yourself for a while.
- Do you think I'm happy? - The doctors
said there's nothing wrong with me.
Yes, you're healthy,
thankfully.
You just need to take care of yourself.
Next year everything will change, you'll see.
- What is it?
- Are you already in bed?
I didn't say "Come in".
You can't come in.
Sorry.
- Do you need anything?
- No.
Good night, then.
Can you make me become a champ?
I've brought everything with me.
I'm sure you can teach me
a lot of things.
If you want, you can give me some exercises
to do, and I can do them by myself.
- Did your mother give you
permission? - Yes.
Come.
My ball!
Why?
That's my ball!
We don't need the ball.
You said you'd train me...
Listen carefully...
The ball follows the foot.
The foot follows the head.
But what does the head follow?
It follows the game plans.
No, the game plans are already
in your head.
Then...
it follows the ball.
No...
The head never follows the ball.
Otherwise, do you know what happens?
What happens?
You lose it.
It rolls away from you.
Try to stay still.
Look outside.
You have to be the first
to see it.
So? Haven't you seen anything?
- No.
- Shh.
Look more carefully.
Down there, on that branch.
There.
It has seen something
moving under the water.
It saw the fish passing by,
and determined its position and speed...
in less than one tenth
of a second.
How do you know
there's a fish under there?
By looking at the kingfisher.
"King"... what?
And I can also tell you
it's not a small fish.
If it had been small, the bird would
have attempted to catch it immediately.
But it needs to be cautious
with a bigger one.
- How did you know that?
- I've learned to watch, to see more.
Pietro!
What happened?
Good morning, madam.
Isn't Pietro here?
Weren't you supposed to do
your homework together?
I wanted to ask him if he wanted
to do a class project with me.
Oh well, I'm off, then.
What's the matter?
I get it; you agree
with my mother.
You're telling me all these things
because you don't want to train me.
Do you think I don't know that one can't
play, if one isn't in shape physically?
Okay, do you want to do
an exercise?
Take off your shoes.
It's quite straight, huh?
Now come here.
Walk on the line.
- How?
- Just walk on it.
Well, it's easy.
Now do it again,
but... "without eyes".
- With my eyes closed?
- Yes.
Piece of cake!
Stop!
- Shoot!
- Do you still think it's easy?
- I thought I was going very straight.
- You have to try again until you get it right.
Come on.
The line is here!
- What is that exercise for?
- Quiet!
First do it,
and then ask questions.
It's cold!
You'll get used to it
in a minute. Come on!
Faster!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, go!
Go!
Good.
Do you want to keep exercising
or is that enough?
I've called all his friends.
I don't know whom else to call.
Let's hope so.
Someone rang the doorbell. Maybe it's him.
I'll call you back, Mirella. Bye.
Am I disturbing you?
I wanted to apologize
about the other night.
- May I...?
- No!
At last!
Where have you been?
What happened?
- Good evening.
- Good evening!
Nothing happened. I was doing
an exercise and I slipped into the water.
One lie after another, huh?
Why didn't you go to Simonetta's?
- She's really stupid.
- Shut up! Don't talk back!
Don't you know
Pietro mustn't strain himself?
It's true: we went to take
some photos and then...
- It was a concentration exercise.
- An "exercise"...
Look at you:
you're all wet!
Come here.
Let me dry you off.
Go and get changed, now.
And give me this sweater; it's not ours.
Please, don't complicate
the situation.
Take your sweater
and leave us alone, now.
You're right,
but he looked very sad.
- I think... - Thank you for your
good will. Now, if you'll excuse me...
These are Pietro's clothes.
Mom!
What is it?
I'm cold.
What's the matter, my love?
You're hot!
I'm cold.
Come on, put this on.
- I'm cold.
- You're hot, my love.
That irresponsible idiot...
You know, Mom?
Thomas has X-ray vision.
- He can see fish through water.
- No! What are you talking about?
Now try to sleep.
Come on.
I'll stay right here with you.
- Are you still cold?
- Yes.
- Now I'm here with you.
- I'm cold.
Now I'll warm you up,
my love.
Huh?
I didn't score.
It's not my fault!
Dad...
Dad, please, help me!
Calm down!
Calm down, my love.
It's a bad dream.
Francesca!
- Come down. It's late.
- Go alone. Pietro is sick.
Come on!
What should I say, this time?
It's the truth.
He has a very high fever.
- Do you need anything?
- No, I'm waiting for the doctor.
- We'll talk later.
- I'll call you. Kiss Pietrino for me.
Bye.
Don't worry, it's nothing.
It's just influenza.
Are you sure?
He looks so strange.
Listen, I've heard you're not
letting Pietro play anymore.
You know there's nothing
wrong with him, don't you?
What does football have
to do with this?
I'm not a psychologist, but...
his father was even keener
on football than he is.
In short, I don't think it's a good idea
not to let him play.
- He's not the same anymore. I don't know
what to do for him. - Francesca...
I think you are the problem,
not him.
I have to go now.
Don't worry; tonight the boy
will be better, you'll see. Bye.
Bye.
He's better. It is you who look
like death warmed up!
Hey...
Today Missiroli was
pissed off as hell!
He said he'll have to send
a doctor to verify your illness.
Yes, I know. He called me.
But I don't give a damn.
Francesca, if you want me to buy
groceries, I'm at your disposal.
- Hello?
- Good evening.
I wanted to know
how Pietro's doing.
You should have seen this coming.
Did you think my son was an aquatic bird?
Can I speak to him?
No, I can't put him on the phone.
He's in bed with a high fever.
Now, excuse me, I'm waiting for
the doctor's call. Goodbye.
(imitating a German accent)
Was it that German, wasn't it?
You're always
in a mood to joke.
Obviously.
You have no children.
(imitating a German accent)
I don't have a boyfriend, either!
Mom, why did you hang up
on Thomas?
You can't do that. He wanted
to speak with me. That's not fair.
I never do anything right.
But I'm doing my best,
Roberto.
You shouldn't have
done that to me.
Leaving me like that...
What should I do about Pietro?
You left me in such a lurch...
- Good morning.
I'm Francesca, Pietro's mom.
Do you remember?
- The football player?
- Yes.
- How is he?
- Much better. Thank you.
- I'm looking for Thomas. - Who can
find him? I haven't seen him for two days!
- He's running after a barn owl.
- Would you do me a favour?
- When you see him, tell him I need
to talk to him urgently. - I will.
- Thank you. Have a nice day.
- Thank you.
Mom!
Mom, aren't you ready yet?
It's not 8:00 yet. It's Sunday morning.
People sleep at this hour.
I'll get it.
May I come in?
It's beautiful!
Is it Beckenbauer's?
No, it's mine.
Thank you.
Come in.
And this is for you.
Often, we have something on our minds
that doesn't allow us to see well.
It is not only
the eyes that see.
That's why you fell
into the water last time.
- Good morning.
- Good morning!
I'm very happy you've come
to visit Pietro.
To give you an example,
your mother thought I was crazy...
because I made you take a "bath"
in that ice-cold water.
Whose brilliant idea was that,
then?
Sometimes too much enthusiasm
to learn leads to some mistake.
But we still have to do
many exercises together,
and take some photos.
This one, for example...
We took it together.
It's beautiful!
But...
Is this a kingfisher
landing on the water?
- No.
- No. Just the opposite.
It's taking flight. See?
It has just grabbed the fish.
Um-hum.
Nice photo.
Even grown-ups don't look
carefully sometimes.
Looking carefully is even harder
than scoring a penalty.
So I can go back
to the oasis with Thomas.
- That's OK with me. But you should ask him.
- That's OK with me, too. But not today.
- Today is "city day".
- What do you mean by "city day"?
Today everyone's going for a walk
in the oasis. It's terrible!
So I'm going to the city,
because it's less crowded.
(in imperfect Italian)
There, I can meet some humans.
(in imperfect Italian) If I spent all my time
with animals, I'd become too "savage".
We say "wild".
"Wild".
So I'm not going
to find you at home.
Now my mother is okay with me going to
the oasis, but I don't know when I'm going.
- I told her I wanted to go when school ends.
- Will she let you?
Sure.
Now she'll let me go.
I might come and see you,
sometime.
- Be good.
- Don't worry.
Don't worry.
Try to understand:
it's the first time we've been apart
since... his father's death.
I know I may sound
a bit stupid...
but, please, you be good, too.
Look!
They're taking off.
How did you know
they were about to take flight?
Look up there.
There's a young hawk.
It had no luck.
- Look carefully: it keeps gliding.
- To make less effort?
No. If it flaps its wings,
it'll become more conspicuous.
That way, it can observe
without being seen.
All animals and humans react
to fast movements,
and become less careful if...
Look!
It chose the wrong time to attack.
There's nothing more it can do.
I wish I could stop this moment
and make it last as long as I like.
What do you mean?
Elaborate.
I don't know...
Like in a photograph,
but better, because when you freeze
an image in a photograph, you're not in it.
You can only look at it.
Stopping time.
Yes, exactly.
It can't be stopped, though.
Children know
how to stop time.
You're different
from other adults.
Someone once told me
I had remained a child.
And that person refused
to see me again.
Who was that person?
Hey, Pietro!
No more "baths"!
Don't rush.
"Rush"? We haven't touched
the ball yet since I came here.
We're not even talking
about football.
I've already told you
that you're good.
The problem is not the foot.
The ball follows the foot.
The foot follows the head.
But what is it that the head follows?
If you don't find this out,
there's no point in training.
If it's so important,
why don't you tell me what it is?
It's not something
you need to know.
It's something
you need to... see.
No one other than
you can see it.
Come on!
Come on.
A new exercise:
hit it with your head.
Come on, go.
It's too high.
You have to do this exercise
until you're able to hit it,
- every time you pass
through here. - Okay.
Come on!
Where are you going, Pietro?
Stop.
- What happened?
- Why did it come at me?
Because you were afraid, and it sensed it.
Animals can sense when you're afraid of them.
And you, why didn't you tell me
it was there?
When I took these photos, I knew
you were going to miss the penalty.
And not because I'm a wizard.
See why you missed it.
My position...
I was unbalanced.
No, Pietro, it wasn't because
of your foot position.
The goalie...
Maybe I didn't see
where the goalie was moving.
Look here:
these eyes don't see anything,
but they know
they're making a mistake.
See?
Your eyes were the cause.
- What are you doing?
- You have to dribble through the poles.
- Our coach, too, makes us do this.
- Yes, but not in the water.
What's the difference?
The mud in the water sticks
to your feet. Your feet get heavier,
and, as a result,
your muscles get stronger.
Are you sure?
Even black-winged stilts make
their chicks do this.
So do it!
Come on!
Come on! Faster!
Go!
Go! Go!
Yes!
Come on!
Faster!
What are you doing?
Yes!
Now come back.
You can walk straight
on the sand,
but now you have
to do it there.
What?!
For the first time, I'll allow you
to do it with your eyes open.
So, are you going
to start or not?
Don't worry.
It's the same exercise.
Open your arms.
Like a flying bird.
Yes.
Hey!
No!
You could do it on the sand.
And now?
Now it's different.
- It's like when you shoot a penalty.
- What do you mean?
You said you never miss one
in training.
Why can't you score
in matches?
In a match it's different.
The spectators look at you.
You think about
the points in the table.
It's more important.
That's exactly the purpose
of the exercise.
Don't think about
the spectators... or the water.
You need to... feel yourself.
Work on your concentration.
Don't think about anything else.
Find your balance.
Huh?
Come on.
Thank you for insisting.
It was a lovely day.
Thank the German,
who's keeping your son!
See? It's not so bad.
I'm doing it for Pietro.
- Yeah, you're doing it for Pietro...
- Yes, I'm doing it for Pietro!
Yeah, sure...
If you tell lies, your nose will grow,
like Pinocchio's.
- I'm not lying!
- Go, go!
Don't say
there's no girl you like.
Come on!
Actually,
a girl in my class likes me.
What about you?
Don't you like her back?
Why did you quit football?
I had an accident.
A teammate broke my knee during
practice. And do you know why?
He wanted to take my place
in the team.
Do you understand?
So I said "No more football",
and I looked for a job
that would take me far away,
where I could live
without people around me,
even though that caused
my wife to leave me.
So it was she who told you
that you had remained a child.
Do you miss her?
And you? Do you think
about your father often?
I no longer think
about him enough.
There are entire days
where I don't think about him,
and there are days
I spend thinking:
"He's not coming back.
He's never coming back."
I don't feel bad, though,
because I know he would be
disappointed if he saw me now.
We often believe
some things belong to the past,
but these things are still
in our hearts.
Like a hawk,
watching from above.
We think it's not there,
but it is there,
ready to come down.
It glides silently,
without flapping its wings.
Maybe I've got it.
You said the head follows something,
but it's not the ball.
It's something
that never stops.
And sometimes it goes slowly,
sometimes it goes very fast.
I've got it!
When I'm afraid, it beats very fast
and I can't think clearly.
Fear and courage
both come from there.
Wake up.
Wake up!
The sun is already up!
- What time is it?
- 5:30.
5:30...
Do you want to stay
in bed all day?
You've finally decided
to come!
Come on,
take your mind off things a bit!
Where are you going?
- I have to make a call.
- To whom?
Hello, this is Francesca.
Do you remember me?
Yes.
They aren't there?
Are they okay?
Listen, do me a favour, then.
When they're back,
please tell Pietro to call me, okay?
Thanks.
Isn't that your mother's car?
She said she'd come tomorrow!
Et voil,
a surprise for you!
Thanks, Mom!
- It's really cool! Look.
- He must have been driving you crazy, huh?
Do you know, Mom, that at 9 p.m. I'm already
in bed? And I'm eating like a horse.
That's a true miracle!
That's our observatory.
I'm going to climb up.
You'll hurt yourself!
Be careful. It could be dangerous!
- Are you letting him go up there alone?
- There's no problem.
Pietro's much better.
- Thank you for your patience, Sir.
- "Sir"?
Well, "Sir" or "Thomas".
I never know when I can drop
the formalities, here in Italy.
Some people call me
Thomas right away.
- But when is it the right moment to drop them?
- Well, this could be a good moment.
This is one of my hides.
- It's invisible!
- Go in.
Please, go in.
From here,
you can see everything.
I've been talking a lot with Pietro
about how to overcome fear.
Maybe I've got him
to overcome his fear,
but I haven't overcome mine.
Francesca...
Francesca!
What are you doing, Pietro?
Explain to me.
Don't you see?
I'm packing my bag.
What happened?
Why are you angry?
You perfectly know why.
You're an asshole! You've been
fooling me all this time!
I never want to see you again!
Pietro?
- Isn't Pietro with you?
- No, he's gone away.
- Where to?
- I don't know, but that's not the problem.
- Francesca, I need to tell you
something. - Not now.
- Excuse me.
- Wait!
Pietro!
Pietro?
Pietro...
I know you're there.
Don't be childish.
I know why you're hiding.
But you're wrong.
Only those who are
afraid, hide.
Real men,
who are able to see
things as they are,
confront them face to face.
They don't hide in the dark.
See? We've become friends.
And the same has happened
to your mother and me.
But for grown-ups
it's more difficult.
If you're hiding, it means
you're still a little child,
and you'll keep being afraid.
So?
I think...
that you don't understand,
and that you're not my friend.
"Gascoigne.
"McManaman!
"He had no difficulty saving it.
It seemed harder."
Can you explain to me
what I'm guilty of?
What did I do to you?
You haven't said a word to me
since you got back.
Pietro?
Pietro, open up.
I think I know why
you're angry with me.
Even if I had a relationship with Thomas,
it wouldn't take anything away from you or Dad.
I don't think he'd be happy
if he could see you.
I think he would, instead.
Your father and I loved
each other very much.
I think that, when you really love someone,
you don't want to see him or her unhappy.
I heard from Thomas.
He wants to say goodbye to you
before leaving.
"Leaving"?
Where's he going?
One more "bath"?
My mother said you're leaving.
I've just come to say goodbye.
Are you walking away like that,
without your ball?
Just when you're ready
to play again?
Really?
Yes.
But you have to do
this exercise first.
Or are you too afraid?
Go.
Why are we sitting like this?
Because it helps us
to concentrate.
Look around.
Look at the sky.
I feel like I'm flying.
Shh.
Guys...
Guys!
Today we have to wash away the dishonour
of that 11-0 in the first half of the season.
As my colleague Sacchi says,
you have to follow the game plans!
Or do you want to get me fired?
If you lose today,
I won't feel humiliated.
I'll feel disappointed.
Today, you have to form
a wall in midfield.
You have to play to death!
To death!
Trillini,
is your mom here?
Go.
Come on!
Play wide!
Well done, Pietro!
Slide-tackle him!
Cut off his legs!
Ref!
Way to go!
I'm gonna send you
to the hospital.
Go!
- Go!
- Come on, go!
Do you feel unwell?
- I feel something.
- What do you feel?
I feel we're going to win.
Go!
Go to the wing!
Slide-tackle him!
Go!
Goal!
Great!
I'm thirsty!
Come, I'll buy you
an orange soda.
Come on, guys,
we can still win!
Yeah, sure...
You, don't move like a sack of
potatoes, or you'll never catch the ball.
Move like a magpie,
that stays still and then jumps.
- It stays still and then jumps.
- Like... what?!
Like a magpie, that stays still
and then jumps.
It stays still and then jumps.
And you, Mottola...
You have to move like a hawk,
silently and agilely.
It's you!
I thought you had left.
Have you seen how well
Pietro is playing?
He seems confident.
There's still
the second half, though.
I think there won't be
any problem for him, now.
No.
Not for him.
And for us?
Did you say "us"?
Yes.
What about us?
Go!
Careful!
- Come on!
- Pass the ball!
Offer resistance!
Go!
Cross!
Cross the ball!
Hey!
- Go!
- Knock him down!
Well done!
Come on, stop him!
Ref!
Come on!
- Go!
- Come on!
Knock him down!
Trip him!
Shoot!
I'm free!
Come on!
Ref!
Penalty for Audace!
Penalty! Penalty! Penalty!
He's limping!
That idiot...
Murderer! Murderer!
You scoundrel!
Fuck off!
That scoundrel kicked you
very hard!
When Pietro was away,
Mottola would shoot penalties.
- Mottola, do you want to shoot it?
- No, I don't feel like it.
Unbelievable!
Hey,
does anyone feel like
shooting this darn penalty?
- I'll shoot it, Coach.
- Are you sure you're up for it?
- Good thing Pietrino will shoot it.
- That jerk!
Are you shitting your pants?
Goal!
Great!
Well done!